Sol M. Linowitz Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Office File, 1778-1999 (Box 136-538)
  - Part A, 1778-1967 (Box 136-291)
    - Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government
      - Interstate Commerce Commission, administrative procedure, 1955-1956, undated, (2 folders)
      - Notes, 1949, undated
    - Committee for a National Trade Policy
      - Foreign income tax provisions in proposed Revenue Act of 1962
      - Speeches and statements by Linowitz and others, 1962, undated
      - Trade expansion bill, 1962, (2 folders) (Box 159)
    - Cooperative Grange League Federation Exchange, 1950-1963, undated, (2 folders)
    - Council for International Progress in Management (USA), New York, N.Y.
      - General correspondence, 1964-1966, undated, (4 folders)
      - International Enterprise Fellowships
        - Correspondence, 1964-1966, (5 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1963-1966, undated (Box 160)
        - Xerox Corp., 1965-1966
    - Council of Social Agencies, Rochester, N.Y., 1950-1956, undated, (2 folders)
    - Council on Foreign Relations
      - Correspondence, 1963-1966, (3 folders)
      - Rochester Committee on Foreign Relations, Rochester, N.Y., 1966
    - Council on World Tensions, New York, N.Y., 1963-1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - Country Beautiful, 1963-1966, (2 folders)
    - Court of Public Opinion (television program) (Box 161)
      - Correspondence
        - 1951, May-1953, Dec., (12 folders)
        - 1954, Jan.-1955, Mar., (14 folders) (Box 162)
        - 1955, Apr.-1957, May, (13 folders) (Box 163)
        - 1957, June-1962, Oct., undated, (8 folders) (Box 164)
      - Discussion topics
        - Academic freedom, 1950-1956, undated
        - Africa, 1953-1954, undated
        - Anglo-American relations, 1953, 1962, undated
        - Asia, 1951-1958, undated
        - China, 1955-1961, undated (Box 165)
        - Congressional investigations and the Fifth Amendment, 1778, 1948-1955, undated, (2 folders)
        - Corruption in government, undated
        - Education, 1954-1955, undated
        - Educational television, 1951, 1958-1959, undated
        - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1953-1955
        - Elections
          - Congressional, 1956, undated
          - Local, 1955, undated
          - Miscellany, 1952-1954, undated
          - Presidential, 1950-1952, undated
        - Farm programs, 1954-1955, undated
        - Federal budget and taxes, 1953-1954, undated (Box 166)
        - Foreign policy, 1951-1963, undated, (2 folders)
        - France, undated
        - “The George Eastman I Knew,” 1953-1954, undated
        - Germany, 1948-1961, undated, (2 folders)
        - “How Can We Meet Today's Tension in the United States?” 1954-1957, undated
        - “How Can We Get the People of the World on Our Side?” 1951-1956, undated
        - Indo-China, 1953-1954, undated
        - Inflation and price controls, 1950-1951, undated (Box 167)
        - Internal security, 1955, undated
        - Israel
          - Miscellany, 1951-1958, undated
          - Writings by Linowitz, 1947, 1956, undated
        - Korea, 1951-1953, undated
        - MacArthur, Douglas (1880-1964), and Harry S. Truman, 1951, undated
        - Middle East, 1946-1959, undated, (2 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1861, 1948-1951, undated
        - Notable books, 1956-1957
        - Nuclear weapons, 1951-1953, undated
        - Nuclear weapons tests and public health, 1961, undated
        - Refugees, 1957-1960, undated (Box 168)
        - Religion and democracy, 1943-1958, undated, (3 folders)
        - Science and government, undated
        - Soviet Union
          - “Are the Russians Winning?” 1958-1959, undated
          - “Can We Make Peace with Russia?” 1953, undated
          - Miscellany, 1948-1956, undated
        - Teenage diplomats program, 1952-1959, undated, (2 folders)
        - Truman, Harry S., 1951-1953, undated
        - United Nations, 1952-1961, undated, (2 folders)
        - Western Europe, 1949-1956, undated, (2 folders) (Box 169)
        - “What Are the Prospects for World Peace?” 1959, undated
        - “What Has Happened to American Morals?” 1959, undated
        - “What Is Happening to American Culture?” 1960, undated
      - Production file
        - Advertising, 1955-1956, undated
        - Miscellany, 1947-1962, undated
        - Program note cards
          - 1951-1954, (7 folders)
          - 1955-1961, undated, (11 folders) (Box 170)
          - Undated, (5 folders) (Box 171)
        - Schedules, 1951-1961, undated, (2 folders)
        - Trademark registration, 1957-1965
    - Crilly, Hugh E., 1951-1953, undated, (2 folders)
    - Democratic Party
      - Democratic National Committee, 1964-1966
      - New York Democratic State Committee (Box 172)
        - Advisory Committee on the Constitutional Convention, 1964-1966, n.d, (3 folders)
        - Advisory Council, 1963-1964, undated, (2 folders)
        - General correspondence, 1959-1966
    - Denker, Henry, 1956-1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - Disarmament, 1956-1964, undated
    - Drosd v. Cleary, 1958
    - E. T. Gilbert Manufacturing Co., 1931-1947, (2 folders) (Box 173)
    - Education
      - Allegheny College, Meadville, Pa., 1966, undated, (2 folders)
      - Association of Governing Boards of State Universities and Allied Institutions
        - Correspondence, 1962-1963, (3 folders)
        - Speech by Linowitz, 1962, undated
      - Babson Institute, Babson Park, Mass.
        - Correspondence, 1965-1966
        - Speeches by Linowitz and others, 1966, undated
      - Brandeis University, Waltham, Mass. (Box 174)
        - Correspondence, 1964-1966, (2 folders)
        - Notes, 1956-1957, 1966, undated
      - Chatham College, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1964-1966
      - Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
        - Advisory Council to the School of International Affairs and Regional Institutes, 1963-1966, undated, (2 folders)
        - Center for Research and Education in American Liberties, 1966, (2 folders)
        - General correspondence, 1966, undated
      - Cornell Law School, Ithaca, N.Y.
        - Advisory Council, 1963-1966
        - Class agent, 1961, undated
        - Cornell Law Association
          - Annual luncheon, 1964, (2 folders)
          - Correspondence, 1959-1964, (5 folders) (Box 175)
          - Miscellany, 1954-1958, undated
          - Notes for speeches by Linowitz, 1952-1956, undated, (2 folders)
        - Cornell Law Forum, 1961-1963
        - Cornell Law Quarterly Dinner, notes for speech by Linowitz, 1951-1955, undated
        - Dedication of Charles Evans Hughes Hall, 1963-1965, undated
        - First-year law students, notes for speech by Linowitz, 1962, undated
        - Frank Irvine Lecture by Linowitz, 1966, Feb. 11
          - Clippings, 1964-1966, undated
          - Correspondence, 1965-1966, (3 folders) (Box 176)
          - Excerpts, 1966, undated
          - Notes, undated
          - Research material, 1951-1966, undated, (2 folders)
          - Text
            - Preliminary drafts, 1966, undated
            - Final versions, 1966, undated
        - General correspondence, 1949-1966, (4 folders) (Box 177)
        - Miscellany, 1949-1958, undated
        - Notes, 1961-1963, undated
        - Photographs, law school dinner, 1953, Apr. 17
        - Presidency offered to Linowitz, 1951, 1962, undated
        - Summer Conference on International Law
          - 1956-1957
          - 1962, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 178)
          - 1964, (2 folders)
          - Undated
      - Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y.
        - Alumni Association, 1961-1966, (2 folders)
        - Board of Trustees, 1966, (3 folders)
        - Clippings, 1961, 1966 (Box 179)
        - Founders' Day, notes for speech by Linowitz, 1957, 1962, undated
        - General correspondence, 1962-1966, (3 folders)
        - Operation Crossroads Africa, 1961-1965
        - Tower Club, 1966, undated
      - Dillard University, New Orleans, La., 1966
      - Eisenhower College, Seneca Falls, N.Y., 1966
      - Hamilton College, Clinton, N.Y.
        - Ad Hoc Committee on the Subject of Honorary Degrees
          - Correspondence, 1964-1966, (3 folders)
          - Nominees, 1959, 1966, undated, (2 folders)
        - Advisory Committee, 1964
        - Alumni Fund, 1959-1960, undated (Box 180)
        - Board of Trustees
          - Correspondence, 1964-1966, (2 folders)
          - Minutes of meetings, 1964-1966
          - Miscellany, 1963-1967, undated
        - Class reunion, 1960, undated
        - Commencement speech by Linowitz, 1965, June 6, (2 folders)
        - Committee on Student Affairs, 1965-1966
        - General correspondence
          - 1955-1960, (2 folders)
          - 1961-1966, (6 folders) (Box 181)
        - Luncheon for business leaders of Rochester, N.Y., 1964
        - Miscellany, 1956, 1961-1966, undated, (2 folders)
        - Planning Committee, 1964-1965, (2 folders)
      - Hampton Institute, Hampton, Va., 1963-1966, undated
      - Kent State University, Kent, Ohio, 1966, undated (Box 182)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence
        - Education, 1965-1966, undated
        - Secondary schools, 1966
        - State universities and community colleges, 1963-1966, (3 folders)
      - Regents Advisory Committee on Educational Leadership, University of the State of New York, Albany, N.Y.
        - Clippings, 1962-1963, undated
        - Conference on Trustee Leadership, New York, N.Y., 1965
          - Correspondence, 1962-1965
          - Speeches and notes
            - By Linowitz, 1964-1965, undated, (3 folders)
            - By others, 1952-1965, undated
        - General correspondence
          - 1963-1964, (2 folders)
          - 1965-1966, (4 folders) (Box 183)
        - Minutes of meetings
          - 1963, Dec.-1966, May, (8 folders)
          - 1966, Sept.-Nov., (2 folders) (Box 184)
        - Questionnaires, 1964-1965
        - Reports
          - 1961-1966, (7 folders)
          - Undated (Box 185)
      - Rochester, N.Y.
        - Board of Education, 1960, 1965-1966, undated
        - Miscellany, 1964-1966
      - Rochester School for the Deaf, Rochester, N.Y.
        - Correspondence
          - 1951-1961, (8 folders)
          - 1962-1966, (2 folders) (Box 186)
        - Miscellany, 1942-1962, undated, (2 folders)
        - Ziegler, Frederick, estate, 1938, 1953-1954, undated, (2 folders)
      - Rosary Hill College, Buffalo, N.Y., 165-1966, undated
      - University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Mich.
        - Correspondence, 1963-1964
        - Speech by Linowitz, 1962
      - University of Rochester, Rochester, N.Y.
        - American Council of Learned Societies
          - Correspondence, 1953-1959
          - Notes and statements, 1953-1954, undated
        - American Mathematical Society, notes for speech by Linowitz, 1956
        - Associates program, 1962-1963
        - B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation at the University of Rochester, 1962-1966 (Box 187)
        - Board of Trustees
          - Correspondence, 1960-1966, (11 folders)
          - Minutes of meetings (Box 188)
            - 1955-1962, (10 folders)
            - 1963-1966, (3 folders) (Box 189)
          - Members, 1960-1967
        - Canada-United States Conference
          - Correspondence, 1954-1960
          - Miscellany, 1954-1958, undated, (2 folders)
        - Capital Campaign Steering Committee
          - Foundations and corporations
            - Ford Foundation, 1966
            - Others, 1960-1966, undated, (4 folders) (Box 190)
          - Medical Faculty Committee, 1964-1965, undated, (2 folders)
          - Minutes of meetings, 1964-1966, (2 folders)
          - Printed matter, 1965-1966
          - Reports on visits to potential donors, 1963-1966
        - College English Association (Box 191)
          - Conferences, 1953-1958, undated, (2 folders)
          - Correspondence, 1954-1960, (2 folders)
        - Commencement speakers, 1876, 1956-1966
        - Committee on the Revision of the By-laws
          - Correspondence, 1954-1961
          - Drafts and notes, 1951-1954, undated
        - Committee on Honorary Degrees, 1960-1966, undated, (3 folders)
        - Corporate Relations Committee
          - Corporate dinners
            - 1956
            - 1957-1959, (3 folders) (Box 192)
          - Correspondence
            - 1952-1957, (8 folders)
            - 1958-1961, undated, (3 folders) (Box 193)
          - Legal issues, 1951-1952, undated
          - Miscellany, 1952-1959, undated, (2 folders)
          - Open house, 1962-1965
          - Prospective donors, 1951-1957, undated, (2 folders)
          - Workbooks, 1955-1956 (Box 194)
        - Division of University Relations, 1962-1965, undated
        - Eastman School of Music
          - Board of Managers, minutes of meetings, 1960-1962, undated
          - Correspondence, 1964-1966, (2 folders)
          - Director of the school, selection process, 1960-1965, undated, (2 folders)
          - Miscellany, 1919, 1932, 1962-1965, undated
          - Reports
            - 1960-1961
            - Undated (Box 195)
        - Educational television
          - Correspondence, 1951-1953
          - Miscellany, 1951-1953, undated
        - Executive Committee
          - Correspondence
            - 1951, Feb-1960, Sept., (7 folders)
            - 1960, Oct.-1966, Oct., (4 folders) (Box 196)
          - Minutes of meetings
            - 1954-1960, (4 folders)
            - 1961-1966, (6 folders) (Box 197)
        - Finance Committee, 1959-1966
        - General correspondence
          - 1949, Mar.-1952, Apr.
          - 1952, May-1956, May, (10 folders) (Box 198)
          - 1956, June-1963, Mar., (11 folders) (Box 199)
          - 1963, Apr.-1966, Oct., undated, (4 folders) (Box 200)
        - Index to meetings of Board of Trustees and Executive Committee, 1956-1967
        - Marshak, Robert Eugene
          - Correspondence, 1963-1965
          - Writings, 1947-1956, undated
        - Memo to the Board (newsletter), 1953-1960, undated
        - Miscellany, 1951-1963, undated, (3 folders)
        - Nominating Committee (Box 201)
          - Correspondence, 1951-1965, (6 folders)
          - Minutes of meetings and notes, 1960-1961, undated
        - Office of University Development
          - Miscellany, 1951-1956, undated, (2 folders)
          - Reports, 1953, 1959
          - Speakers' Committee, 1950-1953, undated, (2 folders)
        - President of the university (Box 202)
          - Candidates, 1949-1950, 1961-1962, (3 folders)
          - De Kiewiet, C. W.
            - Correspondence, 1953-1966, (2 folders)
            - Writings and clippings, 1952-1960, undated
          - Inauguration, 1962-1963
          - Reviews of candidates, 1961-1962, undated, (4 folders)
          - Selection process, 1961-1962, undated, (3 folders) (Box 203)
          - Wallis, W. Allen, 1962-1966, undated, (2 folders)
        - Scholar's Program, 1831, 1952-1956, undated
        - School of Medicine and Dentistry
          - Correspondence, 1955-1966, undated, (4 folders)
          - Miscellany
            - 1954-1960, (3 folders)
            - 1961-1962 (Box 204)
        - Speeches and writings by Linowitz, 1953, 1957, undated
        - State university and community college proposal, 1960-1965, undated
        - Trustees' Advisory Committee for the College of Arts and Sciences
          - Correspondence, 1962-1966
          - Miscellany, 1964-1966, (2 folders)
        - University Senate, 1963-1964, undated
        - Whyte, William Hollingsworth, lecture, 1961, undated
        - Women's enrollment, 1961
      - Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio
        - Assembly on Arms Control
          - Correspondence, 1961-1966
          - Miscellany, 1962, undated
        - Law school, 1961-1962, undated
    - Electro-Networks, Inc., 1961
    - Electroprises, Inc., 1952-1953
    - Elgeet Optical Co., 1962-1963 (Box 205)
    - Employers Mutual Insurance Liability Company of Wisconsin, 1949, 1953-1954
    - Enterprise, Inc.
      - Correspondence, 1959-1962, undated, (4 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1958-1961
    - Exposition Universelle et Internaionale, Brussels, Belgium, 1958
    - Farrington Manufacturing Co., 1964
    - Fay, William A., 1957, undated
    - Federal Woman's Award, Washington, D.C., 1965-1966
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1964-1966
    - Fortnightly Club, Rochester, N.Y., 1953-1966, undated, (3 folders)
    - Foster, Ethyl, 1962-1964, undated (Box 206)
    - Foster, J. T., 1960-1961, undated
    - Freedom House, New York, N.Y., 1965-1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - Front Street project, Rochester, N.Y., 1950-1955, undated
    - Garson, Charles, Jr.
      - Correspondence, 1944-1967
      - General guardian of Ellen C. Garson, a minor, 1931-1951, undated, (3 folders)
      - Wills and other legal documents, 1939-1964
    - General Mills, Inc., 1963, undated
    - Genesee Brewing Co., 1949-1950
    - Genesee Valley Craft Guild, Rochester, N.Y., 1958
    - Goldberg, Maxwell Henry, 1962-1964, undated, (2 folders)
    - Government (Box 207)
      - Advisory Committee on International Organizations, State Department
        - Correspondence, 1962-1966 See also Classified, (8 folders)
        - Meetings, 1962-1966 See also Classified, (4 folders)
        - Members, 1962-1966, undated
        - Miscellany, 1961-1965, undated See also Classified, (2 folders) (Box 208)
        - Notes, 1962-1963, undated
        - Reports
          - “Financial Management of the United Nations System”
            - Clippings, 1963-1963, undated
            - Correspondence, 1963-1964, undated See also Classified, (3 folders)
            - Report, 1963
            - United States budgetary procedures and policies, 1962-1963, undated See also Classified, (3 folders)
          - “Staffing International Organizations”
            - Clippings, 1963-1964, undated
            - Correspondence, 1963-1964 See also Classified, (4 folders) (Box 209)
            - Miscellany, 1962-1965, undated See also Classified, (3 folders)
            - Report
              - Correspondence, 1962-1963
              - Text, 1963, undated See also Classified, (2 folders) (Box 210)
            - Statements by Linowitz, 1962-1963
          - “The Technical Cooperation Programs of the United Nations System”
            - Correspondence, 1963-1964 See also Classified, (2 folders)
            - Miscellany, 1962-1964, undated See also Classified, (2 folders)
            - Report, 1963, undated See also Classified
        - Subcommittee on Peacekeeping Operations
          - Article 19 of the U.N. Charter, 1962-1964 See also Classified, (2 folders)
          - Correspondence, 1963-1965 See also Classified, (2 folders) (Box 211)
          - Miscellany, 1962-1965, undated See also Classified, (3 folders)
          - Statements by Linowitz, 1963, undated
      - American democracy, letter by Linowitz for the Congressional Record, 1966
      - Antipoverty programs
        - Lists, undated
        - Community Action Program, Rochester, N.Y.
          - Correspondence, 1964-1966
          - Miscellany, 1963-1966, undated, (2 folders)
        - Office of Economic Opportunity, Business Leadership Advisory Council
          - Correspondence
            - 1964, Apr.-1965, Feb., (2 folders)
            - 1965, Mar.-1966, Nov., (4 folders) (Box 212)
          - Miscellany, 1964-1966, undated, (4 folders)
        - Speeches and writings by Linowitz, 1963-1966, undated
        - Task Force on Antipoverty Programs in New York City
          - Correspondence, 1964-1966
          - Miscellany
            - 1964-1965
            - 1966, undated (Box 213)
      - Civil rights See Container 223, White House Conference: “To Fulfill These Rights”
      - Economic development
        - Correspondence, 1965-1966
        - Miscellany, 1951, 1965-1966
      - Education
        - International aid
          - Correspondence, 1965-1966, (2 folders)
          - Miscellany, 1965-1966, undated
          - Task Force on International Education, Committee on Education and Labor, House of Representatives, 1965-1966, undated, (2 folders)
        - White House Conference on Education
          - Correspondence, 1965
          - Miscellany, 1965, (2 folders)
      - International development (Box 214)
        - Agency for International Development
          - Consultant, 1961-1965
          - Correspondence, 1961-1966, undated, (3 folders)
        - Citizens' Committee for International Development
          - Articles by Linowitz, 1961, undated
          - Correspondence
            - Set I, 1961-1962, (2 folders)
            - Set II, 1961-1962, undated, (2 folders)
          - Miscellany, 1957, 1961, undated, (2 folders)
        - National Committee for International Development
          - Africa, 1966
          - Bylaws, undated
          - China
            - Correspondence, 1963-1966, undated
            - Miscellany, 1964-1966, undated
          - Clippings, 1961-1966, undated
          - Finance records, 1966 (Box 215)
          - General correspondence
            - 1961, Nov.-1965, Mar., (11 folders)
            - 1965, Apr.-1966, Oct., undated, (12 folders) (Box 216)
          - India
            - Correspondence, 1964-1966
            - Miscellany, 1963-1966 (Box 217)
          - International Chamber of Commerce, United States Council
            - Correspondence, 1965-1966
            - Miscellany, 1963-1967, undated, (2 folders)
          - Meetings, 1964-1966 See also Classified
          - Members and volunteers, 1961-1966, undated, (2 folders)
          - Memoranda and statements, 1961-1966, undated, (3 folders)
          - Miscellaneous reports and articles
            - 1961-1963
            - 1964-1966, undated, (3 folders) (Box 218)
          - Notes, 1964-1966, undated, (2 folders)
          - Offers to volunteer, 1964, undated, (5 folders)
          - Replies to invitations to serve on the Committee, 1964, undated (Box 219)
          - Speeches and writings by Linowitz, 1964-1966, undated, (2 folders)
      - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1964-1966
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1965-1966, (3 folders)
      - Peace Corps
        - Correspondence, 1964-1966
        - Miscellany, 1963-1966, undated, (2 folders)
      - President's General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs
        - Brazil, 1965-1966, undated
        - General correspondence See also Classified
          - 1965, Jan.-June, (2 folders)
          - 1965, Aug.-1966, Nov., (3 folders) (Box 220)
        - Health programs, 1964-1967
        - India, 1965-1966, (2 folders)
        - Meetings, 1965-1966 See also Classified, (5 folders)
        - Memoranda and reports, 1964-1967 See also Classified, (8 folders) (Box 221)
        - Miscellany, 1965-1966, undated, (2 folders)
        - Monthly newsletters
          - 1965
          - 1966, (3 folders) (Box 222)
        - Population crisis, 1955, 1963-1966, (3 folders)
        - Portugal, 1964-1965, n.d, (2 folders)
        - Reports from foreign countries, 1965-1966 See also Classified, (2 folders)
        - Subcommittee on the Private Sector, 1966, undated, (2 folders)
      - President's National Service Program, 1962-1963 (Box 223)
      - Urban affairs, 1965-1966
      - Vietnam, 1966
      - White House, proposed conference on creative thinking, 1965
      - White House Conference on International Cooperation
        - Correspondence, 1965-1966
        - Miscellany, 1965-1966, (3 folders)
      - White House Conference: “To Fulfill These Rights,” 1966, (3 folders)
    - Hadingham, Ronald G., 1943, 1953-1959
    - Hall Window Corp. v. Jefferson Home Improvement Co.
      - Correspondence, 1956-1959, (2 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1957-1959, undated (Box 224)
    - Harris, Beach, Keating, Wilcox, Dale, and Linowitz (law firm), Rochester, N.Y.